Okay, so let's talk about the difference
between CNAME and Alias,
'cause in the exam, that is a very common question
you may get.
So Amazon resources, or AWS resources,
such as Load Balancer, CloudFront, et cetera,
they will expose an Amazon, AWS URL.
So for Load Balancer, it may look like this.
Lb1-123.us-east-2.elb.amazonaws.com.
And maybe you want this to be myapp.mydomain.com.
So for this we'll use, Route 53.
We have two options.
The first one is to use a CNAME.
Remember, a CNAME makes a URL point to any other URL.
So we can map app.mydomain.com to
blabla.anything.com.
Anything you want, right?
So CNAME though, you need to know something about it,
it's only for non root domain.
So we need it to be something.mydomain.com.
It cannot be just mydomain.com.
It has to be something.mydomain.com.
Very important.
Alias now, points a URL to an AWS resource only.
So app.mydomain.com points to, blabla.amazonaws.com.
And it works for both root domain and non root domain.
So it can work for mydomain.com.
On top of it, Alias is free of charge,
and it has a support for native health checks.
So the example has two questions such as hey,
we want to point mydomain.com to our Load Balancer,
should you use CNAME or Alias?
And the answer is, you should use Alias,
because CNAME do no support root domains,
only for non root domains.
So it must be something.mydomain.com.
Once you get, understand this, then this is perfect.
Let's have a look in the hands on tool
to understand what I mean by this.
So currently I have an A record for my root domain,
so I'm going to delete this just for now.
Okay, now I'm going to create a record set.
So let me close everything, here we go.
I'll create a record set
and this is going to be myapp.stephanetheteacher.com.
And first choice is for me to get a CNAME.
And I'll make it a CNAME directly
to the load balancer I have.
So I scroll down, click on load balancer
and I'll select this GNS name right here
and I'll say okay, CNAME, pointing to this,
this is a very valid CNAME,
and it works, I'll click on create.
And as we can see now,
if I go to myapp.stephanetheteacher.com,
as we can see, we get the Hello World directly from
the load balancer which points to the EC2 instance.
So this is working really, really great.
Also what I could be doing, is instead of doing a CNAME,
I could use an Alias record,
because this is a load balancer,
so here I'm doing something inefficient,
I'm pointing directly to an amazon resources
but I don't take advantage of the Alias feature.
So I create a record,
I'll call it myalias
and there I'm going to make this an Alias record,
so click on the Alias yes,
and you can say, okay,
either you choose a target name
and to be honest I'm still confused by how this works
because sometimes it doesn't show what you wanna have.
Or it says you can also type the domain name
for the resource directly in there.
So if I just paste this, it will work and find right away
that it is my load balancer in there.
So I've pasted this and we get an Alias hosted zone ID
so this is perfect.
Click on create and here we go, we have an Alias record
being created.
And so if I try this URL
myalias.stephanetheteacher.com,
I get the exact same result,
pointing to the load balancer
and eu-west-1c.
So in that regards, my CNAME, myapp and myalias,
they do the exact same purpose, one is an Alias record,
one is a CNAME, and so this one is going to be free,
this one going to be paid,
but they achieve sort of the same purpose.
Overall I do recommend for you to use myalias.
As we can see though, in myalias,
we can evaluate the target health right away
by clicking on yes,
and it will directly leverage
the load balancer health checks for this
which is really, really cool.
But for now, just leave it as no.
Okay.
Now let's look at root domain.
So if I go on stephanetheteacher.com,
I can make this an alias and enter the target name in there,
and click on create and this works just fine.
So stephanetheteacher.com,
is an Alias directly to my load balancer.
So my root domain, is an Alias.
And that works just fine.
But if I create a record set and this time,
so let me just delete this one obviously first,
I'll delete this one, confirm.
So I'll make a new one,
stephanetheteacher.com,
but this one I'm gonna get a CNAME pointing to
and my domain name for my load balancer,
which is right here, pointing it and click on create.
Here we get an error, saying the CNAME with the DNS name
is not permitted at apex in zone, stephanetheteacher.com.
So that means that basically I'm trying to create a CNAME
at the root of my domain name, so at the apex of my zone
and that is just not allowed by Route 53.
So I cannot do this.
If I wanted to have stephanetheteacher.com
pointing to my load balancer,
CNAME is not an option, it would make an error.
The only way to do it would be to select an Alias record
and point directly to my load balancer in there.
Click on create, and now let's just test that out.
I'll go to stehanetheteacher.com,
and we'll have to wait just a little bit,
for it to work.
So let me just wait one second,
and they use an incognito window
just to make sure that I have no DNS cache
but here we go, stephanetheteacher.com,
points directly to my load balancer,
and it's replied from my EC2 instance.
So this is perfect,
that just proves that basically Alias records both work
for the root domain and also for sub domains.
Whereas, CNAME just work for sub domains only.
And it is something that you need to know
going into the exam.
I hope you liked this lecture,
I will see you in the next one.