For networking also,
we need to know in and out how to create,
operate and manage a VPC.
Troubleshooting is also very important.
So, we'll look at Amazon VPC
and AWS Direct Connect in this section.
Now, you may be asking me oh, I already know
how to do VPC and I say I hope you do
but trust me, for to know how to do a VPC,
you need to look at this diagram
and understand everything that goes in there.
So, have a good look.
If you know everything in there,
you can skip this session,
if not, I strongly recommend to do this section,
take your time, it is long, there's lots of learning
and we're going to visit a whole new set of concepts.
It takes a lot of time to learn VPC,
it took me a lot of time to learn VPC.
Don't worry, we'll go step by step
and understand this in our time.
Let's get started now.